字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
1014 A.D. YORK, NORTHUMBRIA DAY OF ROYAL COUNCIL MEETING
（公元1014年 諾森比亞地區，約克）
What's in the barrel?
裡面裝的是什麼？
Wine.
是酒
There are so many soldiers.
來了好多士兵
Well, of course.
那是當然的
A great many lords are gathering here today.
今天有很多族長會來這裡
Wow.
哇
And are these lords going to eat all this?
這些都是要給族長們吃的？
You can't be serious.
真的假的？
-You're exaggerating. -No, it's true!
-你常說謊 -我才沒有
The guy was nearly stabbed and didn't even notice.
那傢伙快被刺到，竟然都沒發現
He really is oblivious.
的確像他會做的事
So, what do you think really happened yesterday?
你怎麼看待前幾天發生的事？
There was an assassination attempt.
暗殺王子未遂的事？
The implication is troubling, but we can't entirely ignore the rumors.
雖然這樣說很失禮
So the king prefers Prince Harald over Prince Canute?
所以國王還是傾向於哈羅德王子 而非庫奴特王子吧？
The Canute faction can't be too pleased.
支持庫奴特的人肯定很不是滋味
It's still only a rumor.
這只是傳聞而已
We may have to change our plans.
我們是不是該改變計畫了…
Moreover, Canute has succeeded in bringing Thorkell to his side.
不，托魯克爾也站在庫奴特那邊
And he more than compensates for the loss of Ragnar.
足以彌補少了拉古納爾的損失
Yes, but Thorkell isn't capable of governing.
托魯克爾不懂政治
Prince Canute may not be able to control him.
庫奴特根本控制不了他
Then there are the other two who've recently joined Canute's side.
現在想想 還有一個人加入庫奴特陣營
I believe his name is Askeladd, meaning "of the ashes."
他好像叫阿謝拉特 “滿身灰塵”的意思
That's a name I haven't heard.
我沒聽過這名字
Lords!
全體請起立！
His Majesty the King and His Royal Highness the Prince have arrived!
國王陛下
Look at that mountain of food!
好多食物！
What happened to Thorfinn?
托爾芬怎麼了？
Not sure.
這個嘛
But you needn't worry about having a guard at this time.
您不必擔心安全問題
No one would be so foolish as to attack you here and now.
沒有人會蠢到在這裡動武
Can't you wretches walk any faster? Hurry up!
走快一點，不要拖拖拉拉！
Stupid kid.
笨小孩
Hey!
喂！
What? It's just a kid.
什麼？只是個小孩而已
Hold on!
喂，等一下！
How dare you grab me with your filthy paws!
你竟敢用髒手碰我！
What's with this kid?
這小鬼搞什麼？
Look at us, you little bastard.
混蛋，別當作沒看到
Hey!
喂，說話啊！
Is he for real?
喂
You some kind of joker?
你在小看我們嗎？
Give us whatever you have.
把錢拿出來！
You little--
你竟敢…
Get out of my way!
滾，快讓路！
You morons!
你們這些白痴！
You again?
又是你？
You'll be sentenced later. I can't waste time on a day like this.
之後再決定怎麼處罰你！
Is this a good idea?
你確定沒關係嗎？
I heard he's the prince's personal guard.
我聽說他是王子的護衛之類的…
The prince is attending the Royal Council.
王子正在出席御前會議
His guards aren't wandering the streets at a time like this.
殿下的護衛怎麼可能自己在街上閒晃
You are the eminent lords of Denmark.
丹麥的各位族長
You have done well to gather here today.
感謝你們遠道而來
After pursuing the dream for many years,
多年來的願望終於實現
my dominion over the country of England has finally been formalized.
我現在能正式統治英格蘭這片土地了
This great day has come to pass because of your courageous efforts.
這都是各位辛苦奮戰的成果
Furthermore, my faithful friend Thorkell
此外，我的老朋友托魯克爾
and my dear son Canute
和我的兒子庫奴特
have returned home under the divine protection of the Gods.
都在眾神保佑下回到我的身邊
It is an extraordinary happiness.
我的高興之情難以言喻
I am pleased you have returned, Canute.
我很高興你回來了，庫奴特
Your father is overjoyed.
父親我很高興
Of our new territory, I bestow on you Mercia to govern.
我要將新領土中的麥西亞封給你
We will work together to bring prosperity to this land.
我們攜手將這片土地打造得更美好吧
Thorkell.
托魯克爾
It is my wish that you provide support to my son.
請你協助我兒子，這是我的請求
Gladly.
知道了
Mercia?
麥西亞？
The richest land in all of England?
英格蘭最富饒的土地？
I guess the rumors were unfounded.
看來傳聞就只是個傳聞
Well, you never know.
還很難說呢
He might be saying that precisely because they are true.
或許正因為傳聞是真的，他才這樣說
Gentlemen, I will also reward you according to your merits in battle.
至於各位，我也會根據戰功 賜予你們同等的獎賞
In addition, let us ready all our strength for our next campaign in Ireland.
在下一個戰場愛爾蘭，也請全力以赴
The land of Ireland
愛爾蘭
is where the odious tyrant Brian Boru
正是暴君布萊恩波爾
fought our armies and dealt a bitter loss to our late King Harald.
讓先王哈羅德吃盡苦頭的地方
I  did it!
我贏了！
The king reacted just as I had predicted.
國王的反應跟我預料的一樣
In the battle of wits, I have gained the upper hand.
要比才智的話，是我佔優勢
What a reaction on Floki's face.
弗洛基的表情真不錯
Sorry, but you'll be pulling the short end of the stick from now on.
抱歉，但從今以後你只會居於劣勢
In this fight, I'll be taking the lead.
這場對決由我主導
All the pieces are in place. I alone can make this work!
萬事俱全了
However, gentlemen…
不過各位
this land remains occupied
這片土地上
by impudent men who know not how to respect a king.
還有不懂得尊敬國王的無禮之徒存在
I must address this issue.
我得談談這件事
I sent envoys who offered these kingdoms to become my vassals.
我兩度派遣使者 勸他們對我俯首稱臣
I have made the offer twice.
他們卻果斷地拒絕我所釋出的善意
If rebellion is threatening to take root in the new territory,
若有威脅新領土安寧的反抗勢力發芽
we must spare no effort to weed it out completely!
那我們就該盡全力立即拔除
Wales.
威爾斯
We will show it's people
我們要讓那裡的人
just how much power a real king can wield to reach his goal.
見識一下真正王者的實力
Next spring, we will lead a charge.
明年春天就進攻
Prepare yourselves, gentlemen.
請各位做好準備
Wake up.
起來
Did you hear me?
你沒聽到嗎？
Wake! Up! Now!
快起來！
You've got a visitor!
有人來見你了！
Is it one of Canute's men?
庫奴特的手下？
Turn him away.
叫他走
Why would it be one of Canute's men?
當然不是王子的使者
He's just a sailor.
只是個水手
Thorfinn.
托爾芬
A merchant told me that someone fitting your description had been arrested.
我認識的商人告訴我 有個很像你的人被帶走了
I was alarmed, Thorfinn.
我嚇了一跳，托爾芬
It's got nothing to do with you.
不關你的事
It's been eleven years.
11年了啊？
You have suffered much anguish.
你受了多少苦？
It is just as you said.
就像你說的
I could never understand.
我永遠無法理解
As long as that man is alive, your heart will never be at peace.
只要那個人還活著 你的心永遠不會平靜
If you say you remain unsatisfied…
如果你覺得還不夠
then it must be true.
那就是不夠吧
However…
但是…
I remember our lives as if it were yesterday.
我還記憶猶新
The crackling hearth.
燒得劈啪作響的壁爐
The smell of hearty stew.
燉菜的香氣
Thors.
托爾茲、海爾加、悠瓦
And…
還有…
your smile when you were a child.
你小時候的笑容
I once told you
我跟你說過
about how I was trapped by an ice floe off the coast of Brattahlid.
很久以前，我被困在 格陵蘭的浮冰上，對吧？
The food had run out and my ship was wrecked.
食物沒了，船也毀了
All six of my companions were dead.
六個同伴全都死了
Regardless,
儘管如此
I continued to walk across the ice.
我還是繼續在冰上走著
Do you know why?
你知道為什麼嗎？
Because no matter how violent the sea,
不管大海多麼波濤洶湧
or how frozen the water…
天氣有多麼冰冷
a seaman never gives up his fight with the sea
水手就是該與大海戰鬥
just like a warrior!
就像戰士一樣
This is how we maintain our honor!
我們賭上了自己的榮譽
When Thors left this world,
托爾茲去世的時候
and you disappeared,
你失蹤的時候
I made a promise and put my honor on the line.
我以自己的榮譽發了誓
That's why, Thorfinn,
所以托爾芬
I don't say this for your sake alone.
我說這些不是為了你
It is for my own sake!
而是為了我自己！
I will take you home back to Iceland no matter what!
我一定要把你帶回故鄉冰島！
This is how I will bring honor to the memory of Thors!
這樣我才能報答托爾茲的救命之恩！
Next, we will hear from the lord of Schleswig,
接下來有請什勒斯威格的諸侯
son of Erik,
艾利克之子伊瓦爾大人
Come forth.
請上前
For your victories in battle,
根據你所立的戰功
the king grants you this silver and land in the new territory.
國王陛下賜予你銀子和領地
Accept your reward with honor.
快謝過陛下
It seems the news had no effect on him.
他好像不受影響
He's only just heard it.
只有一瞬間而已
But the blood went from his face when you said "Wales."
你說威爾斯時，他的臉色都變了
Wales.
他的弱點可能與威爾斯有關
We should bear this in mind.
請陛下留意
Slow down a bit. Don't devour everything like a boar.
不要狼吞虎嚥，很難看
Shut up!
吵死了！
This is how I honor the God of the harvest.
這是我對豐收之神表達感謝的方式
Are you trying to get even more gigantic?
你還想變得更高大嗎？真是的
Damn it.
可惡
What the hell was that? This I didn't expect from King Sweyn?
那是怎麼一回事，斯韋恩王？
Has he learned of my relationship with Wales?
他知道我和威爾斯的關係嗎？
No, that's highly unlikely.
不，不可能
I didn't tell Floki.
我沒跟弗洛基說過
And even if he knew,
就算他知道
the king wouldn't redirect his entire army just to antagonize me.
他也不會為了激怒我而全軍出動
Then, maybe it's just be a coincidence?
所以只是巧合嗎？
Never mind, that doesn't matter.
不，無所謂
The problem is that come spring, Wales will be turned into a sea of fire.
問題是春天一到 威爾斯會變成一片火海
Damn it.
可惡
Think.
快想辦法
There is no time.
沒時間了
What can I do before spring?
在春天之前能做什麼？
Have the prince lead a revolt?
讓王子帶頭叛變嗎？
No. In that case, I could only rely on Thorkell's 500 men.
不，我只信任托魯克爾那五百人
We'd be completely outnumbered.
軍事力量的差距還是太大
It will take time to bring the generals to our side.
還需要時間拉攏其他將軍
Perhaps, I could I incite a civil war among the English?
再度挑起英格蘭的內鬥呢？
That's no good! Wales would be the main battlefield.
不行！主戰場還是可能會在威爾斯
War can't be the solution.
別往戰爭方面去想
Besides, the king's assassins
更何況國王的刺客
could take advantage of the confusion and kill Prince Canute.
也可能趁亂暗殺庫奴特王子
Go home?
故鄉…
Now, of all times?
偏偏在這時候？
Far to the west,
遙遠的西方
beyond the sea…
海的另一邊
there is a new land where the fruit is plentiful
有著豐富物產
and waves of green grass ripple across the hills and meadows.
和廣闊草原的新天地
This is Vinland.
那裡叫做“文蘭”
Thorfinn.
托爾芬
Vinland!
文蘭！
Come back home, and once things settle down,
先回故鄉，等塵埃落定
we can look for Vinland together!
我們一起去尋找文蘭吧！
Why?
為什麼？
Because you yourself said it!
你自己說的！
You said Thors wanted to go there.
你說托爾茲想去那裡
Thors resettled in Iceland to escape the fighting.
托爾茲為了逃離戰爭才去了冰島
If he were alive…
如果他還活著
I am sure Thors would have wanted to find this place.
他也一定會去尋找文蘭
A place without slavery or war,
那裡沒有奴隸或戰亂
where everyone can live in peace
人人都能和平共處
in a rich and abundant land.
土地富饒肥沃
We can do it.
我們來創造那樣的國度吧
In Vinland…
在文蘭…
In Vinland, I'm sure we could do it!
如果在文蘭，我們一定可以做到！
By the way,
對了
about Wales.
說到威爾斯
When I was pursuing you, you evaded me by disappearing into it.
被我在追殺時 你們就是逃到那裡的吧
What trick did you use to pull that off?
你是怎麼辦到的？
How did you get the Welsh to help a Danish army?
為什麼威爾斯人會幫你這個丹麥人？
My mother's grave is there.
我母親的墳墓在那裡
That land…
那片土地是…
is my home.
我的故鄉
My country.
我的國家
The land is poor.
雖然土地貧瘠，但人民都很自豪
It is the country my mother loved.
那是我母親深愛的國家
I see.
這樣啊
Well in that case,
怎麼說呢
I'm sorry.
真是可惜
I'd appreciate if you didn't tell anyone.
這些話別說出去
I know.
我知道
Retainer to Prince Canute,
庫奴特殿下的隨從
son of Olaf, Askeladd.
沃拉夫之子阿謝拉特
Come forth.
請上前
Here we go.
真是的…
I wonder why
為什麼
my luck runs out
像我這樣的人
at the very last moment.
每到關鍵時刻就不走運？